welcome back to AP US History in under 3
minutes no time for intros let's get
into it now we start talking about the
causes of the American Revolution which
usually brings up two fields of thought
philosophical causes and direct causes
this video will be on the direct causes
being the British taxation so the basic
question to ask here is with so much
diverse peoples in the colonies of the
Americas living different lives how
exactly is this random group of people
going to come together enough to incite
a revolution the answer is a common
enemy and a few other reasons the
British had become heavily in debt
because of the Seven Years War and
therefore started taxing their colonies
in the Americas through acts 1764 the
Sugar Act was passed where the British
taxed imported sugar 1765 the Stamp Act
was passed which required colonists to
purchase stamped paper for any document
1767 the towns headend acts are passed
which put taxes on imported goods like
paper paint and tea these three acts
finally started getting colonists to
think the fact is the American colonies
were subject to British laws including
taxes but had no representatives in the
British Parliament to voice their
interests or concerns the British argued
that they did have a voice by proxy but
the colonists denied it the Sons of
Liberty was a group who boycotted and
protested against the British the Stamp
Act Congress convened where
representatives from several colonies
meant to formally protest the Stamp Act
also of note was efforts of people like
Ben Franklin who helped rally colonists
into one United culture in 1770
continued British military presence in
the colonies caused the Boston Massacre
where English soldiers fired upon
revolting colonists and killed five in
1773 Britain passed the Tea Act which
put attacks on tea which everybody was
drinking at the time this caused the
Boston Tea Party where colonists dumped
the tea into the British Harbor this all
LED Britain to passing the Intolerable
Acts in 1774 which closed the British
Harbor and gave a hit to local
governments by 1775 these issues along
with others like restrictions on
Westward Expansion and stuff we'll go
over in next video had set the stage for
the outbreak of the American Revolution
on the screen now are AP style questions
for this topic pause now
I'll put the answers on the screen
now see you in the next one